https://northhawaiihospice.org/privacy-policy/

Contact
North Hawaii Hospice Caring for North Hawaii's Families since 1986
Privacy Policy
Your Information. Your Rights. Our Responsibilities.
This notice describes how medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information. Please review it carefully.
Your Rights
You have the right to:
Get a copy of your paper or electronic medical record
You can ask to see or get an electronic or paper copy of your medical record and other health information we have about you.
We will provide a copy or a summary of your health information, usually within 30 days of your request. We may charge a reasonable, cost-based fee.
Correct your paper or electronic medical record
You can ask us to correct health information about you that you think is incorrect or incomplete.
We may say “no” to your request, but we’ll tell you why in writing within 60 days.
Request confidential communication
You can ask us to contact you in a specific way (for example, home or office phone) or to send mail to a different address.
We will say “yes” to all reasonable requests.
Ask us to limit the information we share
You can ask us not to use or share certain health information for treatment, payment, or our operations. We are not required to agree to your request, and we may say “no” if it would affect your care.
If you pay for a service or health care item out-of-pocket in full, you can ask us not to share that information for the purpose of payment or our operations with your health insurer. We will say “yes,” unless a law requires us to share that information.
Get a list of those with whom we’ve shared your information
You can ask for a list (accounting) of the times we’ve shared your health information for six years prior to the date you ask, who we shared it with, and why.
We will include all the disclosures except for those about treatment, payment, and health care operations, and certain other disclosures (such as any you asked us to make). We’ll provide one accounting a year for free, but will charge a reasonable, cost-based fee if you ask for another one within 12 months.
Get a copy of this privacy notice
You can ask for a paper copy of this notice at any time, even if you have agreed to receive the notice electronically. We will provide you with a paper copy promptly.
Choose someone to act for you
If you have given someone medical power of attorney or if someone is your legal guardian, that person can exercise your rights and make choices about your health information.
We will make sure the person has this authority and can act for you before we take any action.
File a complaint if you believe your privacy rights have been violated
You can voice your complaint by contacting us at 65-1328 Kawaihae Rd. Kamuela, HI 96743, Telephone: 808-885-7547 and ask for Katherine Werner, or FAX to (808) 930-6633.
You can file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Office for Civil Rights by sending a letter to 200 Independence Avenue, S.W., Washington, D.C. 20201, calling 1-877-696-6775, or visiting www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/complaints/.
We will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint.
Your Choices
For certain health information, you can tell us your choices about what we share. If you have a clear preference for how we share your information in the situations described below, talk to us. Tell us what you want us to do, and we will follow your instructions.
In these cases, you have both the right and choice to tell us to:
Share information with your family, close friends, or others involved in your care
Share information in a disaster relief situation
If you are not able to tell us your preference, for example if you are unconscious, we may go ahead and share your information if we believe it is in your best interest. We may also share your information when needed to lessen a serious and imminent threat to health or safety.
In these cases we never share your information unless you give us written permission:
Marketing purposes
In the case of fundraising:
We may contact you for fundraising efforts, but you can tell us not to contact you again
Our Uses and Disclosures
We typically use or share your health information in the following ways:
Treat you
We can use your health information and share it with other professionals who are treating you.
Example: A doctor treating you for an injury asks another doctor about your overall health condition.
Run our organization
We can use and share your health information to run our practice, improve your care, and contact you when necessary.
Example: We use health information about you to manage your treatment and services.
Bill for your services
We can use and share your health information to bill and get payment from health plans or other entities.
Example: We give information about you to your health insurance plan so it will pay for your services.
How else can we use or share your health information? We are allowed or required to share your information in other ways – usually in ways that contribute to the public good, such as public health and research. But, we have to meet many conditions in the law before we can share your information for these purposes.
Help with public health and safety issues
We can share health information about you for certain situations such as:
Preventing disease
Helping with product recalls
Reporting adverse reactions to medications
Reporting suspected abuse, neglect, or domestic violence
Preventing or reducing a serious threat to anyone’s health or safety
Do research
We can use or share your information for health research.
Comply with the law
We will share information about you if state or federal laws require it, including with the Department of Health and Human Services if it wants to see that we’re complying with federal privacy law.
Respond to organ and tissue donation requests
We can share health information about you with organ procurement organizations.
Work with a medical examiner or funeral director
We can share health information with a coroner, medical examiner, or funeral director when an individual dies.
We can use or share health information about you
For workers’ compensation claims
For law enforcement purposes or with a law enforcement official
With health oversight agencies for activities authorized by law
For special government functions such as military, national security, and presidential protective services
Respond to lawsuits and legal actions
We can share health information about you in response to a court or administrative order, or in response to a subpoena.
Our Responsibilities
We are required by law to maintain the privacy and security of your protected health information.
We will let you know promptly if a breach occurs that may have compromised the privacy or security of your information.
We must follow the duties and privacy practices described in this notice and give you a copy of it.
We will not use or share your information other than as described here unless you tell us we can in writing. If you tell us we can, you may change your mind at any time. Let us know in writing if you change your mind.
For more information see:
www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/understanding/consumers/index.html.
www.hhs.gov/ocr/privacy/hipaa/understanding/consumers/noticepp.html.
Changes to the Terms of this Notice
We can change the terms of this notice, and the changes will apply to all information we have about you. The new notice will be available upon request, in our office, and on our Website.
Effective Date of Notice: 9/23/2013
Website Privacy Policy
North Hawaii Hospice’s privacy policy extends to all information presented when visiting or accessing our Website. Any information supplied is retained solely for the purpose of keeping clients and visitors informed of North Hawaii Hospice’s services, publications, special offers, announcements, and events. We will not sell, supply, or grant access to this information by other parties at any time.
Terms of Use
PERMISSION
North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. may collect and use personal information that you submit on our Website in any manner consistent with our Privacy Policy or disclosed elsewhere in the Website. By submitting your personal information on the Website, you are giving consent and permission for any use consistent with the Privacy Policy statement or elsewhere on the Website where your information was submitted. This consent will be presumed by Hospice Hawaii, unless you state otherwise at the time of submission.
DATA USAGE
North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. is interested in improving our Website and may develop and offer new features and services. We monitor aggregated data regarding use of the site for marketing purposes and to continue to improve and promote use of North Hawaii Hospice’s Website. North Hawaii Hospice may share aggregated data with third parties collectively and anonymously. No personal information will be revealed which would identify the site user in any way.
PRIVACY POLICY EXPECTATIONS
North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. has two exceptions to these limits on use of personal information: North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. may monitor and, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is required, disclose information to protect the security, property, assets and/or rights of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. from unauthorized use, or misuse, of the site or anything found at the site. North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. may disclose information when required by law; however, only to the extent necessary and in a manner that seeks to maintain the privacy of the individual.
COOKIES
Cookies are pieces of information or data sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies to make your visit to our Website better. For example, cookies allow us to recognize you when you re-enter our Website so that you may not have to sign-in each time you visit. Cookies also allow us to count the number of unique and return visitors who use our site. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser to notify you when you’ve received a cookie or, alternatively, to refuse to accept cookies. It is important to note that you may not be able to use certain features on our Website if you choose not to accept cookies, such as the online donations module. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance their experience on our site.
Primarily we use cookies to collect and maintain aggregated data (such as number of visitors) which help us to see which areas are most visited by our site users which, in turn, allows us to improve our site content for a better user experience. The information you provide through a cookie does not show your personal identity, only data on site usage, which we review in aggregate in an effort to enhance the user experience on our website.
LINKS TO OTHER SITES
North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. does provide links to other Websites that we believe might offer you useful information and services. We are very careful in selecting appropriate Websites; however, those sites may not have the same Privacy Policy as North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. We are not responsible for the Privacy Policies or content of these sites. If you have a concern regarding these other Websites, please contact the site owners directly.
SECURE INFORMATION
Correspondence via email is not secure, unless clearly noted otherwise. There is always a risk when sending sensitive information via email. Please take this into consideration when emailing Hospice Hawaii.
LICENSE AND USE OF SITE
North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. grants you a limited license to access and make personal use of this site. This license does not include any resale or commercial use of this site or its contents; any collection and use of any product listings, prices or descriptions; any copying or downloading of account information for the benefit of another merchant; any use of data mining, robots or similar data gathering and extraction tools; or any derivative use of this site or its contents. This site or any portion of this site may not be duplicated, copied, reproduced, visited, sold, resold or otherwise exploited for any commercial purpose without express written consent of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. You may not use any meta tags or any other “hidden text” utilizing Hospice Hawaii’s name or trademarks without the express written consent of Hospice Hawaii. You may not frame or utilize framing techniques to enclose any trademark, logo or other proprietary information (including images, text, page layout, or form) of Hospice Hawaii without its express written consent. Any unauthorized use terminates the license granted by Hospice Hawaii.
RIGHT TO RESERVE PRIVACY POLICY
Hospice Hawaii reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, without notice of changes. Any change to the Privacy Policy will be displayed on the website.
ERRORS AND INACCURACIES
The goal of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. is to provide complete, accurate, up-to-date information on its site. Unfortunately, it is not possible to ensure that any site is completely free of human or technological errors. This site may contain typographical mistakes, inaccuracies or omissions, and some information may not be complete or current. North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. reserves the right to correct any errors, inaccuracies or omissions, including after an order has been submitted, and to change or update information at any time without prior notice.
COPYRIGHT
All content included on this site, such as text, graphics, logos, button icons, images, data compilations and software, is the property of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. or its content suppliers and protected by United States and international copyright laws. The compilation of all content on this site is the exclusive property of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc.and protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. All software use on this site is the property of North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. or its software suppliers and protected by United States and international copyright laws.
TRADEMARKS
All trademarks, service marks and trade names employed by North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. are proprietary to North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. or other respective owners that have granted North Hawaii Hospice, Inc. the right and license to use such trademarks, service marks and trade names, and are protected by U.S. and international trademark laws.
Share this...FacebookTwitterLinkedinPinterest
Can we help? Have questions? Please call us at (808) 885-7547 or e-mail us at info@northhawaiihospice.org
Contact Us
65-1328 Kawaihae Road
Kamuela, Hawaii 96743
Phone: 808-885-7547
Fax: 808-885-5592
Email us
Find us on Facebook
Receive our Email Newsletter
Sign Up
Home · Contact · Privacy Policy · Non-discrimination Notice Need a Language Interpreter? English | Tagalog | Japanese | Ilocano | Chinese | Spanish | Hawaiian | Korean | Samoan | Vietnamese | Marshallese | Trukese | French | German | Tongan Copyright © 2020 North Hawaii Hospice · Sitemap · Designed by Websites with Aloha
